Chapter 3. The spout in.
Entering that gable ended spout in, you found yourself in a wide, low,
straggling entry, with old-fashioned Wayne Scots, reminding one of the
bullwarks of some condemned old craft.
On one side hung a very large oil painting so thoroughly bes and every way
defaced that in the unequal crosslights by which you viewed it, it was only by
diligent study and a series of systematic visits to it and careful
inquiry of the neighbors that you could anyway arrive at an understanding of its
purpose. such unaccountable masses of shades and shadows that at first you
almost thought some ambitious young artist in the time of the New England
hags had endeavored to delineate chaos bewitched. But by dent of much and
earnest contemplation and off-re repeated ponderings, and especially by
throwing open the little window towards the back of the entry, you might at last
come to the conclusion that such an idea, however wild, might not be altogether unwarranted.
But what most puzzled and confounded you was a long, limber, portentious black
mass of something hovering at the center of the picture, over three blue, dim,
perpendicular lines floating in a nameless yeast, a bogggy, soggy,
squitchy picture, truly enough to drive a nervous man distracted. Yet was there
a sort of indefinite half-attained unimaginable sublimity about it that
fairly froze you to it, till you involuntarily took an oath with yourself
to find out what that marvelous painting meant. Ever and a non a bright but alas
deceptive idea would dart you through.
It's the black sea in a midnight gale.
It's the unnatural combat of the four primal elements. It's a blasted heath.
It's a hyperorean winter scene. It's the breaking up of the icebound stream of
time. But at last all these fancies yielded to that one portentious
something in the picture's midst that once found out, and all the rest were
plain. But stop. Does it not bear a faint resemblance to a gigantic fish,
even the great Leviathan himself?
In fact, the artist's design seemed this, a final theory of my own, partly
based upon the aggregated opinions of many aged persons with whom I conversed
upon the subject. The picture represents a Cape Horner in a great hurricane, the
half-founded ship weltering there with its three dismantled masts alone
visible, and an exasperated whale purposing to spring clean over the
craft, as in the enormous act of impaling himself upon the three mast
heads. The opposite wall of this entry was hung over with a heathenish array of
monstrous clubs and spears. Some were thickly set with glittering teeth
resembling ivory saws. Others were tufted with knots of human hair, and one
was sickle-shaped with a vast handle sweeping round like the segment made in
the new moan grass by a longarmed mower.
You shuddered as you gazed and wondered what monstrous cannibal and savage could
ever have gone at death harvesting with such a hacking, horrifying implement.
Mixed with these were rusty old whailing lances and harpoons, all broken and
deformed. Some were storied weapons.
With this once long last, now wildly elbowed, 50 years ago did Nathan Swain
kill 15 whales between a sunrise and a sunset. And that harpoon, so like a
corkcrew now, was flung in the Javan seas and run away with by a whale years
afterward slain off the Cape of Blanco.
The original iron entered nigh the tail, and like a restless needle sojourning in
the body of a man, traveled full 40 ft, and at last was found embedded in the hump.
Crossing this dusky entry and on through yawn low arched way, cut through what in
old times must have been a great central chimney with fireplaces all round, you
enter the public room, a still duskier place as this, with such low, ponderous
beams above, and such old wrinkled planks beneath that you would almost
fancy you trod some old crafts cockpits, especially of such a howling night when
this corner anchored old ark rocked so furiously On one side stood a long, low shelf-like
table covered with cracked glass cases, filled with dusty rarities gathered from
this wide world's remotest nooks.
Projecting from the further angle of the room stands a darkl looking den, the
bar, a rude attempt at a right whale's head. Be that how it may, there stands
the vast arched bone of the whale's jaw, so wide a coach might almost drive
beneath it. Within are shabby shelves ranged round with old decanters,
bottles, flasks, and in those jaws of swift destruction, like another cursed
Jonah, by which name indeed they called him, bustles a little withered old man
who, for their money, dearly sells the sailor's deliriums and death.
Abominable are the tumblers into which he pours his poison, though true
cylinders without, within the villainous green goggling glasses deceitfully
tapered downwards to a cheating bottom.
Parallel meridians rudely pecked into the glass surround these footpads
goblets. Fill to this mark, and your charge is but a penny. To this, a penny
more, and so on to the full glass, the cape horn measure which you may gulp
down for a shilling.
Upon entering the place, I found a number of young seaman gathered about a
table, examining by a dim light the diverse specimens of scrimshander.
I sought the landlord, and telling him I desired to be accommodated with a room,
received for answer that his house was full, not a bed unoccupied.
But have asked, he added, tapping his forehead, you ain't no objections to
sharing a hopaneer's blanket, have you?
I suppose you're going away, Ling, so you better get used to that sort of thing.
I told him that I never like to sleep
too in a bed, that if I should ever do so, it would depend upon who the
harpineer might be, and that if he, the landlord, really had no other place for
me, and the harpooner was not decidedly objectionable, why, rather than wander
further about a strange town on so bitter a night, I would put up with the
half of any decent man's blanket. I thought so. All right, take a seat.
Supper. You want supper? Supper will be ready directly.
I sat down on an old wooden settle carved all over like a bench on the
battery. At one end, a ruminating tar was still further adorning it with his
jack knife, stooping over and diligently working away at the space between his
legs. He was trying his hand at a ship under full sail, but he didn't make much
headway, I thought. At last some four or five of us were summoned to our meal in
an adjoining room. It was cold as Iceland, no fire at all. The landlord
said he couldn't afford it. Nothing but two dismal tallow candles, each in a
winding sheet. We were fain to button up our monkey jackets and hold to our lips
cups of scalding tea with our half frozen fingers. But the fair was of the
most substantial kind. Not only meat and potatoes, but dumplings. Good heavens.
dumplings for supper. One young fellow in a green box coat addressed himself to
these dumplings in a most direful manner.
My boy, said the landlord, you'll have the nightmare to a dead certainty.
Landlord, I whispered, "That ain't the harpooner, is it?" "Oh no," said he,
looking sort of diabolically funny. "The harpineer is a dark complexion chap. He
never eats dumplings. He don't. He eats nothing but steaks and he likes them
rare. The devil he does, says I. Where is that harpooner? Is he here? He'll be
here for long was the answer. I could not help it, but I began to feel
suspicious of this dark complexioned harpooner. At any rate, I made up my
mind that if it so turned out that we should sleep together, he must undress
and get into bed before I did.
Supper over. The company went back to the barroom. when knowing not what else
to do with myself, I resolved to spend the rest of the evening as a looker on.
Presently a rioting noise was heard without. Starting up, the landlord
cried, "That's the grandpas' crew. I seed her reported in the offing this
morning. A three years voyage and a full ship. Harrah, boys, now we'll have the
latest news from the Fiji's."
A tramping of seab boots was heard in the entry. The door was flung open, and
inrolled a wild set of mariners enough, enveloped in their shaggy watch coats,
and with their heads muffled in woolen comforters, all bearned and ragged, and
their beards stiff with icicles, they seemed an eruption of bears from
Labrador. They had just landed from their boat, and this was the first house
they entered. No wonder then that they made a straight wake for the whale's
mouth the bar when the wrinkled little old Jonah there officiating soon poured
them out brimmers all round. One complained of a bad cold in his head,
upon which Jonah mixed him a pitch-like potion of gin and molasses, which he
swore was a sovereign cure for all colds and catters, whatever, never mind of how
longstanding, or whether caught off the coast of Labrador or on the weather side
of an ice island. The liquor soon mounted into their heads, as it
generally does, even with the errantest toppers newly landed from sea, and they
began capering about most obstreporously.
I observed, however, that one of them held somewhat aloof, and though he
seemed desirous not to spoil the hilarity of his shipmates by his own
sober face, yet upon the whole he refrained from making as much noise as
the rest, this man interested me at once, and since the sea gods had
ordained that he should soon be my shipmate, though a sleeping partner one,
so far as this narrative is concerned, I will here venture upon a little
description of him. He stood a full 6 ft in height with noble shoulders and a
chest like a coffer dam. I have seldom seen such brawn in a man. His face was
deeply brown and burnt, making his white teeth dazzling by the contrast, while in
the deep shadows of his eyes floated some reminiscences that did not seem to
give him much joy. His voice at once announced that he was a southerner, and
from his fine stature I thought he must be one of those tall mountaineers from
the Alaganian Ridge in Virginia. When the realry of his companions had mounted
to its height, this man slipped away unobserved, and I saw no more of him
till he became my comrade on the sea. In a few minutes, however, he was missed by
his shipmates, and being, it seems, for some reason, a huge favorite with them,
they raised a cry of, "Bulkington!
Bulkington! Where's Bulkington?" and darted out of the house in pursuit of him.
It was now about 9:00, and the room seeming almost supernaturally quiet
after these orgies, I began to congratulate myself upon a little plan
that had occurred to me just previous to the entrance of the seaman.
No man prefers to sleep too in a bed. In fact, you would a good deal rather not
sleep with your own brother. I don't know how it is, but people like to be
private when they are sleeping. And when it comes to sleeping with an unknown
stranger in a strange inn in a strange town, and that stranger a harpooner,
then your objections indefinitely multiply. Nor was there any earthly
reason why I, as a sailor, should sleep two in a bed more than anybody else. For
sailors no more sleep two in a bed at sea than bachelor kings do ashore. To be
sure they all sleep together in one apartment. But you have your own hammock
and cover yourself with your own blanket and sleep in your own skin. The more I
pondered over this harpooner, the more I abominated the thought of sleeping with
him. It was fair to presume that being a harpooner his linen or woolen as the
case might be would not be of the tidiest, certainly none of the finest. I
began to twitch all over. Besides, it was getting late, and my decent
harpooner ought to be home and going bedwards. Suppose now he should tumble
in upon me at midnight. How could I tell from what vile hole he had been coming?
Landlord, I've changed my mind about that harpineer. I shant sleep with him.
I'll try the bench here.
Just as you please. I'm sorry I can't spare you a tablecloth for the mattress
and it's a plaguy rough board here feeling of the knots and notches but
wait a bit scrimshander I've got a carpenters's plane there in the bar wait
I say and I'll make you snug enough so saying he procured the plane and with
his old silk handkerchief first dusting the bench vigorously set to planing away
at my bed but while grinning like an ape the shavings flew right and left till At
last the plain iron came bump against an indestructible knot. The landlord was
near spraining his wrist, and I told him, for heaven's sake, to quit. The bed
was soft enough to suit me, and I did not know how all the planing in the
world could make ider down of a pine plank. So gathering up the shavings with
another grin, and throwing them into the great stove in the middle of the room,
he went about his business, and left me in a brown study.
I now took the measure of the bench and found that it was a foot too short, but
that could be mended with a chair, but it was a foot too narrow, and the other
bench in the room was about 4 in higher than the planained one, so there was no
yoking them. I then placed the first bench lengthwise along the only clear
space against the wall, leaving a little interval between for my back to settle
down in. But I soon found that there came such a draft of cold air over me
from under the sill of the window that this plan would never do at all,
especially as another current from the rickety door met the one from the
window, and both together formed a series of small whirlwinds in the
immediate vicinity of the spot where I had thought to spend the night. The
devil fetched that harpineer, thought I, but stop. Couldn't I steal a march on
him, bolt his door inside, and jump into his bed, not to be wakened by the most
violent knockings? It seemed no bad idea, but upon second thoughts, I
dismissed it. For who could tell but what the next morning, so soon as I
popped out of the room, the harpineer might be standing in the entry, all
ready to knock me down. Still looking around me again and seeing no possible
chance of spending a sufferable night unless in some other person's bed, I
began to think that after all I might be cherishing unwarrantable prejudices
against this unknown harpooner. Thinks I I'll wait a while. He must be dropping
in before long. I'll have a good look at him then, and perhaps we may become
jolly good bedfellows after all. There's no telling.
But though the other borders kept coming in by ones, twos, and threes, and going
to bed, yet no sign of my harpooner.
Landlord, said I, what sort of chap is he? Does he always keep such late hours?
It was now hard upon 12:00.
The landlord chuckled again with his lean chuckle, and seemed to be mightily
tickled at something beyond my comprehension.
No, he answered. Generally, he's an early bird. Early to bed and early to
rise. Yes, he's the bird what catches the worm. But tonight he went out to
peddling, you see, and I don't see what on earth keeps him so late, unless maybe
he can't sell his head. Can't sell his head? What sort of a bamboozlingly story
is this you're telling me? Getting into a towering rage. Do you pretend to say,
landlord, that this harpooner is actually engaged this blessed Saturday
night, or rather Sunday morning, in pedalling his head around town?
That's precisely it, said the landlord, and I told him he couldn't sell it here.
The markets overstocked.
With what, shouted I heads, to be sure.
Ain't there too many heads in the world?
I tell you what it is, landlord, I said quite calmly. You'd better stop spinning
that yarn to me. I am not green.
Maybe not, taking a stick out and whittling a toothpick. But I rather
guess you'll be done brown if that air harper hears you a slander in his head.
I'll break it for him, said I, now flying into a passion against this
unaccountable furago of the landlords.
It's broke already, said he. Broke, said I. Broke, do you mean? certain, and
that's the very reason he can't sell it, I guess.
Landlord, said I, going up to him as cool as Mount Heekla in a snowstorm.
Landlord, stop whittling. You and I must understand one another, and that too
without delay. I come to your house and want a bed. You tell me you can only
give me half of one, that the other half belongs to a certain harpooner. And
about this harpooner whom I have not yet seen, you persist in telling me the most
mystifying and exasperating stories, tending to beget in me an uncomfortable
feeling towards the man whom you designed for my bedfellow, a sort of
connection, landlord, which is an intimate and confidential one in the
highest degree. I now demand of you to speak out and tell me who and what this
harpooner is, and whether I shall be in all respects safe to spend the night
with him. And in the first place you will be so good as to unsay that story
about selling his head, which if true, I take to be good evidence that this
harpooner is stark mad, and I have no idea of sleeping with a madman. And you,
sir, you I mean, landlord, you sir, by trying to induce me to do so knowingly,
would thereby render yourself liable to a criminal prosecution?
Well, said the landlord, fetching a long breath. That's a pretty long sermon for
a chap that rips a little now and then, "But be easy, be easy. This here
harpooner I've been telling you of, has just arrived from the South Seas, where
he bought up a lot of bomb New Zealand heads, great curios, you know, and he
sold all of them but one. And that one he's trying to sell tonight cuz
tomorrow's Sunday and it would not do to be selling human heads about the streets
when folks is going to churches. He wanted to last Sunday, but I stopped him
just as he was going out the door with four heads strung on a string for all
the earth like a string of enions.
This account cleared up the otherwise unaccountable mystery and showed that
the landlord, after all, had no idea of fooling me. But at the same time, what
could I think of a harpooner who stayed out of a Saturday night clean into the
holy Sabbath, engaged in such a cannibal business as selling the heads of dead idoltors?
Depend upon it, landlord, that harpooner is a dangerous man. He pays regular, was
the rejoinder. But come, it's getting dreadful late. You'd better be turning
flukes. It's a nice bed. S and me slept in that air bed the night we was
spliced. There's plenty of room for two to kick about in that bed. It's an
almighty big bed. That why, before we give it up, S used to put our Sam and
little Johnny in the foot of it. But I got a dreaming and sprawling about one
night, and somehow Sam got pitched on the floor and came near breaking his
arm. After that, Sal said it wouldn't do. Come along here. I'll give you a
glimp in a jify. And so, saying, he lighted a candle and held it towards me,
offering to lead the way. But I stood irresolute. When looking at a clock in
the corner, he exclaimed, "I vomit Sunday. You won't see that hopping
tonight. He's come to anchor somewhere.
Come along then. Do come, won't you come?" I considered the matter a moment,
and then upstairs we went. And I was ushered into a small room, cold as a
clam, and furnished, sure enough, with a prodigious bed, almost big enough
indeed, for any four harpooners to sleep a breast. There, said the landlord,
placing the candle on their crazy old sea chest that did double duty as a wash
stand and center table. There, make yourself comfortable now, and good night
to you. I turned round from eyeing the bed, but he had disappeared.
Folding back the counterpane, I stood over the bed. Though none of the most
elegant, it yet stood the scrutiny tolerable well. I then glanced around
the room, and besides the bedstead and center table, could see no other
furniture belonging to the place, but a rude shelf, the four walls, and a
papered fireboard representing a man striking a whale. Of things not properly
belonging to the room, there was a hammock lashed up and thrown upon the
floor in one corner, also a large seaman's bag containing the harpooner's
wardrobe, no doubt in lie of a land trunk. Likewise, there was a parcel of
outlandish bone fish hooks on the shelf over the fireplace and a tall harpoon
standing at the head of the bed. But what is this on the chest? I took it up
and held it close to the light and felt it and smelt it and tried every way
possible to arrive at some satisfactory conclusion concerning it. I can compare
it to nothing but a large doormat ornamented at the edges with little
tinkling tags, something like the stained porcupine quills round an Indian
moccasin. There was a hole or slit in the middle of this mat as you see the
same in South American ponchos. But could it be possible that any sober
harpooner could get into a doormat and parade the streets of any Christian town
in that sort of guys? I put it on to try
it, and it weighed me down like a hamper, being uncommonly shaggy and
thick, and I thought a little damp, as though this mysterious harpooner had
been wearing it of a rainy day. I went
up to it in a bit of glass stuck against
the wall, and I never saw such a sight
in my life. I tore myself out of it in
such a hurry that I gave myself a kink
in the neck. I sat down on the side of the bed, and commenced thinking about
this headpedling harpooner in his doormat. After thinking some time on the
bedside, I got up and took off my monkey jacket, and then stood in the middle of
the room, thinking. Then I took off my coat and thought a little more in my
shirt sleeves. But beginning to feel very cold now, half undressed as I was,
and remembering what the landlord said about the harpooners not coming home at
all that night, it being so very late, I made no more ado, but jumped out of my
pantaloons and boots, and then, blowing out the light, tumbled into bed, and
commended myself to the care of heaven.
Whether that mattress was stuffed with corn cobs or broken crockery there is no
telling but I rolled about a good deal and could not sleep for a long time. At
last I slid off into a light doze and had pretty nearly made a good offing
towards the land of nod when I heard a heavy footfall in the passage and saw a
glimmer of light come into the room from under the door. Lord save me thinks I
that must be the harpineer the infernal headpedler.
But I lay perfectly still and resolved not to say a word till spoken to.
Holding a light in one hand and that identical New Zealand head in the other,
the stranger entered the room, and without looking towards the bed, placed
his candle a good way off from me on the floor in one corner, and then began
working away at the knotted cords of the large bag I before spoke of as being in
the room. I was all eagerness to see his face, but he kept it averted for some
time while employed in unlacing the bag's mouth. This accomplished, however,
he turned round when, good heavens, what a sight, such a face. It was of a dark
purplish yellow color here and there, stuck over with large blackishl looking
squares. Yes, it's just as I thought.
He's a terrible bed fellow. He's been in a fight, got dreadfully cut, and here he
is, just from the surgeon. But at that moment he chanced to turn his face so
towards the light that I plainly saw they could not be sticking plasters at
all, those black squares on his cheeks.
They were stains of some sort or other.
At first I knew not what to make of this, but soon an inkling of the truth
occurred to me. I remembered a story of a white man, a whaleman too, who falling
among the cannibals had been tattooed by them. I concluded that this harpooner,
in the course of his distant voyages, must have met with a similar adventure.
And what is it, thought I, after all?
It's only his outside. A man can be honest in any sort of skin. But then,
what to make of his unearly complexion?
That part of it, I mean, lying round about and completely independent of the
squares of tattooing. To be sure, it might be nothing but a good coat of
tropical tanning, but I never heard of a hot sun tanning a white man into a
purplish yellow one. However, I had never been in the South Seas, and
perhaps the sun there produced these extraordinary effects upon the skin.
Now, while all these ideas were passing through me like lightning, this
harpooner never noticed me at all. But after some difficulty having opened his
bag, he commenced fumbling in it, and presently pulled out a sort of a
tomahawk and a seal skin wallet with the hair on. Putting these on the old chest
in the middle of the room, he then took the New Zealand head, a ghastly thing
enough, and crammed it down into the bag. He now took off his hat, a new
beaver hat. When I came nigh singing out with fresh surprise, there was no hair
on his head, none to speak of, at least, nothing but a small scalp knot twisted
upon his forehead. His bald purplish head now looked for all the world like a
mild skull. Had not the stranger stood between me and the door, I would have
bolted out of it quicker than I ever bolted a dinner. Even as it was, I
thought something of slipping out the window, but it was the second floor
back. I am no coward, but what to make of this headpedling purple rascal
altogether past my comprehension.
Ignorance is the parent of fear, and being completely non-plust and
confounded about the stranger, I confessed I was now as much afraid of
him, as if it was the devil himself who had thus broken into my room in the dead
of night. In fact, I was so afraid of him that I was not game enough just then
to address him, and demand a satisfactory answer concerning what seemed inexplicable in him.
Meanwhile, he continued the business of undressing, and at last showed his chest
and arms. As I live, these covered parts of him were checkered with the same
squares as his face. His back, too, was all over the same dark squares. He
seemed to have been in a 30 years war, and just escaped from it with a sticking
plaster shirt. Still more, his very legs were marked as if a parcel of dark green
frogs were running up the trunks of young palms. It was now quite plain that
he must be some abominable savage or other shipped aboard of a whaleman in
the South Seas and so landed in this Christian country. I quake to think of
it, a peddler of heads, too. Perhaps the heads of his own brothers. He might take
a fancy to mind. Heavens, look at that tomahawk.
But there was no time for shuddering, for now the savage went about something
that completely fascinated my attention and convinced me that he must indeed be
a heathen. Going to his heavy grego or raffle or dreadnot which he had
previously hung on a chair, he fumbled in the pockets and produced at length a
curious little deformed image with a hunch on its back and exactly the color
of a 3 days old Congo baby. remembering the imbalmed head at first I almost
thought that this black mannequin was a real baby preserved in some similar
manner. But seeing that it was not at all limber and that it glistened a good
deal like polished ebony, I concluded that it must be nothing but a wooden
idol, which indeed it proved to be. For now the savage goes up to the empty
fireplace and removing the papered fireboard sets up this little
hunchbacked image like a tenpin between the and irons. The chimney jams and all
the bricks inside were very sy that I thought this fireplace made a very
appropriate little shrine or chapel for his Congo idol. I now screwed my eyes
hard toward the half-hidden image feeling but ill at ease meantime to see
what was next to follow. First he takes about a double handful of shavings out
of his grego pocket and places them carefully before the idol. Then laying a
bit of ship biscuit on top and applying the flame from the lamp, he kindled the
shavings into a sacrificial blaze.
Presently, after many hasty snatches into the fire, and still hastier
withdraws of his fingers, whereby he seemed to be scorching them badly, he at
last succeeded in drawing out the biscuit. Then blowing off the heat and
ashes a little, he made a polite offer of it to the little negro, but the
little devil did not seem to fancy such dry sort of fair at all. He never moved
his lips. All these strange antics were accompanied by still stranger guttural
noises from the devote who seemed to be praying in a sing song, or else singing
some pagan somdy or other, during which his face twitched about in the most
unnatural manner. At last extinguishing the fire, he took his idol up very
unceremoniously and bagged it again in his grego pocket as carelessly as if he
were a sportsman bagging a dead woodcock.
All these queer proceedings increased my uncomfortableness, and seeing him now
exhibiting strong symptoms of concluding his business operations and jumping into
bed with me, I thought it was high time, now or never, before the light was put
out, to break the spell in which I had so long been bound. But the interval I
spent in deliberating what to say was a fatal one. Taking his tomahawk from the
table, he examined the head of it for an instant, and then holding it to the
light with his mouth at the handle, he puffed out great clouds of tobacco
smoke. The next moment the light was extinguished, and this wild cannibal
tomahawk between his teeth, sprang into bed with me. I sang out. I could not
help it now, and giving a sudden grunt of astonishment, he began feeling me.
Stammering out something, I knew not what, I rolled away from him against the
wall, and then conjured him, whoever or whatever he might be, to keep quiet, and
let me get up and light the lamp again.
But his guttural responses satisfied me at once that he but ill comprehended my
meaning. "Who devil you?" he said at last. "You no speak yey, damn me, I kill
ye." And so saying, the lighted tomahawk began flourishing about me in the dark.
Landlord, for God's sake, Peter Coffin, shouted I. Landlord, watch. Coffin,
angel, save me. Speaky. Telly me who he be, or damn me, I kill you. Again,
growled the cannibal, while his horrid flourishings of the tomahawk scattered
the hot tobacco ashes about me, till I thought my linen would get on fire. But
thank heaven, at that moment the landlord came into the room, light in
hand, and leaping from the bed, I ran up to him.
Don't be afraid now, said he, grinning again. Quiqu here wouldn't harm a hair
of your head. Stop your grinning, shouted I. And why didn't you tell me
that that infernal harpooner was a cannibal? I thought you'd know it.
Didn't I tell you he was a peddling heads around town? But turn flukes again
and go to sleep. Quig, look here. You sabby me, I sabby you. This man sleepy
you. You sabi me sabi plenty grunted Quequ puffing away at his pipe and sitting up in bed.
You get in, he added, motioning to me with his tomahawk and throwing the
clothes to one side. He really did this in not only a civil but really a kind
and charitable way. I stood looking at him a moment. For all his tattooings he
was on the whole a clean, cumblyl looking cannibal. What's all this fuss I
have been making about? thought I to myself. The man's a human being just as
I am. He has as much reason to fear me
as I have to be afraid of him. Better sleep with a sober cannibal than a drunken Christian.
Landlord, said I, tell him to stash his tomahawk there, or pipe, or whatever you
call it. Tell him to stop smoking, in short, and I will turn in with him. But
I don't fancy having a man smoking in bed with me. It's dangerous. Besides, I
ain't insured. This being told to Quiquake, he at once complied, and again
politely motioned me to get into bed, rolling over to one side as much to say,
I won't touch a leg of you.
Good night, landlord, said I. You may go. I turned in and never slept better in my life.